A Guide to the E. Ingraham Company Records 1980.0034
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series III: Correspondence, 1868-1962
  - Correspondence
    - P - T, 1927 (Box 56)
    - U - W, 1927 (Box 57)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1928
    - Purchasing, C - U, 1928 (Box 58)
    - Purchasing, W - Z, 1928 (Box 59)
    - General, A - K, 1928
    - General, L - W, 1928 (Box 60)
    - Sample Box, 1928 (Box 61)
    - A - Kh, 1929
    - Purchasing, Kr - Z, 1929 (Box 62)
    - General, A - I, 1929
    - General, I - S, 1929 (Box 63)
    - General, T - Z, 1929 (Box 64)
    - Purchasing, A - K, 1930
    - Purchasing, L - S, 1930 (Box 65)
    - Purchasing, Sc - W, 1930 (Box 66)
    - General, A - F, 1930
    - General, G - W, 1930 (Box 67)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1931
    - Purchasing, C - L, 1931 (Box 68)
    - Purchasing, M - U, 1931 (Box 69)
    - Purchasing, W, 1931 (Box 70)
    - General, A - W, 1931
    - General A - O, 1931
    - General, P - Z, 1931 (Box 71)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1932
    - Purchasing, Cl - Me, 1932 (Box 72)
    - Purchasing, Mi - Se, 1932 (Box 73)
    - Purchasing, Sey - W, 1932 (Box 74)
    - General, A - B, 1932
    - General, C - Z, 1932 (Box 75)
    - Sample Box, 1932
    - Sample Box, 1932 (Box 76)
    - Purchasing, A - Cl, 1933
    - Purchasing, Co - K, 1933 (Box 77)
    - Purchasing, K - S, 1933 (Box 78)
    - Purchasing, S - W, 1933 (Box 79)
    - General, A - D, 1933
    - General, E - H, 1933 (Box 80)
    - Quotations, 1933
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1934 (Box 81)
    - Purchasing, C - I, 1934 (Box 82)
    - Purchasing, K - R, 1934 (Box 83)
    - Purchasing, S - W, 1934 (Box 84)
    - General, A - D, 1934
    - General, E - W, 1934 (Box 85)
    - Purchasing, A - Ca, 1935
    - Purchasing, Ch - K, 1935 (Box 86)
    - Purchasing, K - S, 1935 (Box 87)
    - Purchasing, S - W, 1935 (Box 88)
    - General, A - I, 1935
    - General, C - W, 1935 (Box 89)
    - Purchasing, B - C, 1936
    - Purchasing, C - I, 1936 (Box 90)
    - Purchasing, K - R, 1936 (Box 91)
    - Purchasing, R, 1936 (Box 92)
    - General, A - F, 1936
    - General, H - W, 1936 (Box 93)
    - Sample Box, A - G, 1936
    - Sample Box, C - J, 1936 (Box 94)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1937
    - Purchasing, C - L, 1937 (Box 95)
    - Purchasing, M - S, 1937 (Box 96)
    - Purchasing, S - W, 1937 (Box 97)
    - General, B - K, 1937
    - General, K - W, 1937 (Box 98)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1938
    - Purchasing, C - I, 1938 (Box 99)
    - Purchasing, K - R, 1938 (Box 100)
    - Purchasing, S, 1938 (Box 101)
    - General, A - W, 1938
    - General, W, 1938 (Box 102)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1939
    - Purchasing, C - K, 1939 (Box 103)
    - Purchasing, K - U, 1939 (Box 104)
    - Purchasing, U - W, 1939 (Box 105)
    - General, B - N, 1939
    - General, N - Wa, 1939 (Box 106)
    - General, We, 1939 (Box 107)
    - Purchasing, A - C, 1940
    - Purchasing, C - Ma, 1940 (Box 108)
    - Purchasing, Mn - W, 1940 (Box 109)
    - General, A - K, 1940
    - General, L - W, 1940 (Box 110)
    - Sample Box, P - R, 1940
    - Charts for list of correspondence saved from E. Ingraham Co., 1941-1947
    - A - C, 1941 (Box 111)
    - Ca - G, 1941 (Box 112)
    - Ge - Li, 1941 (Box 113)
    - Lo - R, 1941 (Box 114)
    - S - Z, 1941 (Box 115)
    - A - Ba, 1942
    - Be - E, 1942 (Box 116)
    - F - M, 1942 (Box 117)
    - N - Y, 1942 (Box 118)
    - A - Ec, 1943 (Box 119)
    - Ed - M, 1943 (Box 120)
    - M - Z, 1943 (Box 121)
    - A - Bo, 1944
    - Br - I, 1944 (Box 122)
    - I - R, 1944 (Box 123)
    - S - Z, 1944 (Box 124)
    - Sample Box, W, 1944
    - A - B, 1945
    - Ba - I, 1945 (Box 125)
    - I - Z, 1945 (Box 126)
    - A - H, 1946 (Box 127)
    - H - U, 1946 (Box 128)
    - U - Z, 1946 (Box 129)
    - A - C, 1947
    - D - Mc, 1947 (Box 130)
    - Mi - Z, 1947 (Box 131)
    - A - Ar, 1954 (Box 132)
    - Ar - Do, 1954 (Box 133)
    - Dr - O, 1954 (Box 134)
    - P - U, 1954 (Box 135)
    - U - Z, 1954 (Box 136)
    - A - Ar, 1955 (Box 137)
    - Ar, 1955 (Box 138)
    - Ar - B, 1955 (Box 139)
    - C, 1955 (Box 140)
    - D - Et, 1955 (Box 141)
    - Eu - G, 1955 (Box 142)
    - G - I, 1955 (Box 143)
    - I - K, 1955 (Box 144)
    - K - M, 1955 (Box 145)
    - M - Mc, 1955 (Box 146)
    - Mc - Me, 1955 (Box 147)
    - Mi - Na, 1955 (Box 148)
    - Ne - Q, 1955 (Box 149)
    - R - Se, 1955 (Box 150)
    - Se, 1955 (Box 151)
    - Sh - Wer, 1955 (Box 152)
    - Wes - Z, 1955 (Box 153)
    - A - Ar, 1956
    - Ar - Av, 1956 (Box 154)
    - B - Bi, 1956 (Box 155)
    - Bl - C, 1956 (Box 156)
    - D - I, 1956 (Box 157)
    - J - L, 1956 (Box 158)
    - Ma - Mc, 1956 (Box 159)
    - Mc - Ra, 1956 (Box 160)
    - Re - Se, 1956 (Box 161)
    - Se - Sz, 1956 (Box 162)
    - T - Z, 1956 (Box 163)
    - A - D, 1957
    - D - Z, 1957 (Box 164)
    - A, 1958
    - B - K, 1958 (Box 165)
    - L - P, 1958 (Box 166)
    - P - S, 1958 (Box 167)
    - T - Z, 1958 (Box 168)
    - A - C, 1959
    - C - I, 1959 (Box 169)
    - I - P, 1959 (Box 170)
    - O - V, 1959 (Box 171)
    - V - Z, 1959 (Box 172)
    - M - R, 1959 (Box 173)
    - S - R, 1959 (Box 174)
- Series IV: General Accounts, 1852-1959
  - General Ledger and index, 1852-1900; (15 vols.) (Box 186, Box 187, Box 184, Box 185, Box 182, Box 183, Box 180, Box 181, Box 178, Box 179, Box 176, Box 177, Box 188, Box 175, Box 189)
  - Daybook and journal, 1857-1921; (32 vols.) (Box 196, Box 197, Box 194, Box 195, Box 200, Box 201, Box 198, Box 199, Box 215, Box 216, Box 202, Box 214, Box 219, Box 220, Box 217, Box 218, Box 210, Box 211, Box 212, Box 213, Box 207, Box 208, Box 209, Box 203, Box 204, Box 205, Box 206, Box 193, Box 192, Box 191, Box 190, Box 221)
  - Trial Balance Ledger, 1876-1889; (2 vols.) (Box 223, Box 222)
  - General Accounts scrapbook, 1883-1884 (Box 224)
  - Check Book, 1876-1882 (Box 225)
  - General accounts scrapbook, 1881-1887; (2 vols.) (Box 226)
  - Check Book, (3 vols.)
    - 1880-1881
    - 1910-1911
    - 1915-1916
  - Bills payable ledger, 1870-1896; (4 vols.)
  - Cash Book, 1881-1887
  - Petty cash, 1870-1874
  - Bank Book, 1970-1872; (3 vols.)
  - Ledger posting records
    - 1921-1923 (Box 227)
    - 1924-1926 (Box 228)
    - 1927-1928 (Box 229)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 230)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 231)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 232)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 233)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 234)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 235)
    - 1941-1944 (Box 236)
    - 1944-1947 (Box 237)
    - 1947 (Box 238)
  - Accounts payable records, 1938-1947; (8 vols.) (Box 246, Box 245, Box 244, Box 243, Box 242, Box 241, Box 240, Box 239)
  - Accounts receivable ledger, 1938-1947; (11 vols.) (Box 251, Box 252, Box 249, Box 250, Box 247, Box 248, Box 257, Box 256, Box 255, Box 254, Box 253)
  - Accounts receivable ledger, (4 vols.) (Box 258)
    - 1904-1917
    - 1921-1931
    - 1921-1941
    - 1932-1942
  - Stocks and bonds purchase ledger, 1913-1916
  - Bank deposit books, 1915-1918; (4 vols.)
  - Cash book, (4 vols.)
    - 1919-1922
    - 1931-1932
  - Ledger Index, 1936-1937
  - General Ledger, 1944-1945
- Series V: Purchasing, 1861-1959
  - Inventory Ledger, 1861-1895; (2 vols.) (Box 259)
  - Inventory of pinions, 1890-1904; (3 vols.)
  - Materials purchased and sales register, 1901-1924; (9 vols.) (Box 267, Box 268, Box 265, Box 266, Box 263, Box 264, Box 261, Box 262, Box 260)
  - Purchase orders, 1906-1916; (7 vols.) (Box 269)
  - Inventory of tools and equipment, 1899 (Box 270)
  - Coal purchase ledger, 1902-1912
  - Inventory of watches and clocks, 1903-1913
  - Purchase ledger, 1912-1917
  - General office record, 1912-1959
  - Brass purchases, 1924-1940 (Box 270)
  - Records of production materials, 1952-1953 (Box 271)
- Series VI: Labor, undated, 1866-1964
  - Payroll ledger, 1866-1895; (18 vols.) (Box 284, Box 289, Box 286, Box 285, Box 288, Box 287, Box 274, Box 275, Box 272, Box 273, Box 278, Box 279, Box 276, Box 277, Box 282, Box 283, Box 280, Box 281)
  - 1937-1940
  - 1942-1944
  - Time books, 1890; (2 vols.) (Box 290)
  - General correspondence and records, 1936-1959; (22 folders)
  - Arbitration record, 1945-1958 (Box 291)
  - Benefit plans, 1942-1954
  - Bonus list, 1922
  - Employment policies, 1947
  - Federal credit union, mutual aid association, and community welfare fund, 1948
  - Job rating book, undated
  - Labor turnover reports, 1928-1947
  - Retirements plans, 1941-1947
  - Union records
    - Agreements, 1941-1964; (4 folders)
    - Bulletins, 1941
    - Circulars, 1947-1948
    - Dues, 1949
    - Grievances, 1942-1946
    - Hearings, 1942-1946
    - Negotiations, 1942-1962; (4 folders)
    - Publications, 1942-1962
  - Payroll computation book, 1914-1916 (Box 292)
  - Payroll, 1919-1927
  - Statistics, 1925-1949
  - Turnover and production, 1926; (2 folders)
  - 1933-1934
  - Salaried employees
    - Correspondence, 1933-1955
    - Financial records, 1933-1955; (2 folders)
  - Legal correspondence, 1943-1949
  - War labor mobilization, 1943-1946
- Series VII: Production, undated, 1902-1959
  - Inventory of raw materials, 1902-1905; (2 vols.) (Box 293, Box 294)
  - Inventory of raw materials, 1927-1930 (Box 295)
  - Inventory of raw materials, 1951-1935 (Box 296)
  - Special dial orders, 1908-1916; (5 vols.) (Box 297)
  - Weekly production by pieces, 1914-1925; (11 folders) (Box 298)
  - Watch production ledger, 1922-1959
  - War productions records
    - Clock allotment by War Production Board, 1943
    - Copper conservation order, 1942
    - Employment reports, 1943-1945
    - Fuel surveys, 1941
    - Gasoline ration applications, 1942-1944
    - Interoffice correspondence, 1943-1945
    - Brass inventory, 1943
    - Steel inventory, 1943
    - Metal conservation, 1942-1944
    - Office of Price Administration adjustment orders, 1945-1946
    - Plant and equipment surveys, 1942-1943
    - Plant report of operation shipments, 1942-1945; (4 folders)
    - WPB releases, 1945
  - Production report, 1947, 1955
  - Production orders, 1955
  - Case shop records
    - Profit and loss reports, 1937-1939; (16 folders) (Box 299)
    - Finished orders, 1937; (2 folders)
    - Finished orders, 1933-36; (4 folders) (Box 300)
    - Total costs, 1938-1941; (6 folders)
    - Cost estimates, 1933-1935; (5 folders)
    - Cost estimates, 1933-1940; (5 folders) (Box 301)
    - Cost estimates, 1940-1941; (11 folders) (Box 302)
    - Labor costs, 1937-1938; (13 folders)
    - Labor costs, 1938-1941; (15 folders) (Box 303)
    - Production, 1942; (2 folders)
    - Production, 1938-1942; (5 folders) (Box 304)
    - Production and shipments, 1941-1946; (8 folders)
    - Purchases, 1934-1942; (9 folders)
    - Purchases, 1942-1946; (4 folders) (Box 305)
    - Plant and equipment, 1917-1946; (6 folders)
    - War work, 1941-1946; (31 folders)
    - War work, 1941-1945; (12 folders) (Box 306)
    - Samples, 1941-1943; (20 folders)
  - Movement shop cost records, 1933-1937; (5 folders)
  - Printing plates, 1933-1937 (Box 307)
    - Factory exterior, undated (Box 307)
    - Factory interior and equipment, undated
    - Unidentified individual, undated
  - Bomb fuse parts (4 objects) with explanatory documents, 1942-1945 (Box 308)
- Series VIII: Sales, undated, 1856-1970
  - Sales records ledger, 1856-1914; (15 vols.) (Box 309)
  - Sales record ledger, 1914-1929; (5 vols.) (Box 310)
  - Sales record ledger, 1921-1938; (23 vols.) (Box 317, Box 313, Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 332, Box 333, Box 311, Box 312, Box 328, Box 329, Box 330, Box 331, Box 318, Box 319, Box 320, Box 321, Box 327, Box 326, Box 325, Box 324, Box 322, Box 323)
  - Sales order book, 1858-1922; (7 vols.) (Box 334)
  - Railroad freight bills, 1878-1881 (Box 335)
  - Invoices, 1852-1892; (7 vols.) (Box 336)
  - Invoices, 1893-1914; (6 vols.) (Box 337)
  - Invoices, 1917-1929; (5 vols.) (Box 338)
  - Sales statistics book, (2 vols.) (Box 339)
    - 1883-1890
    - 1922
  - Discount books, 1916; (2 vols.)
  - Sales ledger sheets, 1919-1920
  - A - B, undated (Box 340)
  - C - K, undated (Box 341)
  - L - R, undated (Box 342)
  - S - Z, undated (Box 343)
  - Price lists, 1870-1880 (Box 344)
  - Sales charts, 1916-1930
  - Record shipment card samples, 1924-1948; (2 folders)
  - Customer ledger, 1925
  - Customer letters, 1927-1942
  - Sales order book, 1943-1948
  - List of Sentinel Distributors, 1953-1954; (2 folders)
  - Chicago sales campaign, 1955; (2 folders)
  - Electrical Merchandising manufacturers' representative, 1957
  - District sales bulletin, 1958-1959
  - Catalogs, 1881-1935; (27 folders) (Box 345)
    Location of Copies or Alternate Formats
    Digital surrogates of these catalogs available.
  - Catalogs, 1936-1937; (9 folders) (Box 346)
  - Miscellaneous catalogs, undated
  - Nelson Brown Company clock catalogs, undated
  - Company brochures, 1944-1970
  - Illustrated advertisements
    - E. Ingraham Company, undated
    - Other clock companies, undated
- Series IX: Subsidiary Companies, 1869-1966
  - American Coal Company (Box 347)
    - General Ledger, 1869-1871
  - S & S Company
    - General Ledger, 1882-1884
    - Sales register, 1882-1884
    - Cash sales, 1882-1884
  - Press Circulation Company
    - Correspondence, 1903-1904
  - Case Wheel & Manufacturer Company
    - Bill book, 1889 (Box 348)
  - Bristol Realty Company
    - Financial Statements, 1936-1946
  - E-Town Corporation
    - Financial statements, 1955-1961
  - Ingraham Canadian Clock Company
    - Financial statements, 1959-1966
  - A. Schatz & Sons
    - Financial statements, 1964
- Series X: Photographs, map, and blueprints, undated, 1885-1964
  - Photographs (Box 349)
    - Company executives & personnel, 1885-1964
    - Factory exterior, 1875-1945
    - Factory interior, 1906-1964
    - Clocks and watches, 1910-1971
    - Album: Factory and products, 1914-1945
  - Oversized photos (Box 350)
    - Key to main door of original plant, 1859-1887
    - Home of Mr. & Mrs. Ingraham, 1890
    - Company buildings (4), 1915 (Map-case 21:238)
    - Dudley Ingraham, 1929
    - Charles P. Davies: Buyer for Butler Brothers, 1931
      - Walter Ingraham, 1936
    - Edward Ingraham, undated
    - Elmer Stockton: salesman and manager, undated
    - H. Porter, Superintendent, undated
    - Old case shop, undated
    - Group photo of company executives, undated
  - Clockmakers of Bristol, 1937; (6 vols.) (Box 351)
    - Clockmakers
    - History
    - Wooden movements
    - Brass movements, (2 vols.)
    - Miscellaneous documents
  - Maps, drawings, and blueprints (Map-case 21:238)
    - Factory drawings, 1925-1932; (4 each)
    - Factory blueprint, 1928
    - Plant plan: case division, 1928
    - Land purchased from H.C. Thompson Clock Company, 1929
    - Property blueprint, 1934
    - Topography blueprint, 1937
    - Factory and neighborhood blueprint, First District, Bristol, CT, undated